Guide to the Robert Sabatino Lopez Papers
Yale University Library
- Research and Writing Files, 1932-1985; Series III; 1.75' (4 boxes)
  - Articles and chapters
    - "Italien: Die Stadwirtschaft", no date (Box 18, Folder 331)
    - "The Medieval Cities", no date (Box 18, Folder 332-333)
    - Miscellaneous, 1932-1953 (Box 18, Folder 334)
    - "Pasta and Nutrition", 1983 (Box 18, Folder 335)
    - En 1943: Une Société génoise pour le commerce eurasien; "Alfonso El Sabio e la pecora merino", 1985, no date (Box 19, Folder 336)
    - Unfinished articles, 1969-1970 (Box 19, Folder 337)
  - Lectures
    - Collège de France, 1976, no date (Box 19, Folder 338)
    - "The Enchanting Model and the Distorting Mirror", 1978 (Box 19, Folder 339)
    - Harvard lectures on the Middle East, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 340)
    - Medieval women, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 341-342)
  - Notebooks, no date (Box 19, Folder 343-344)
  - Notebooks, no date (Box 20, Folder 345-349)
  - Notes
    - Arabic currency, 1960-1963, no date (Box 20, Folder 350)
    - "Byzantinica", no date (Box 20, Folder 351)
    - China, India, etc., no date (Box 20, Folder 352)
    - Genoa, 1968-1977, no date (Box 20, Folder 353-354)
    - Ideto Gentile, no date (Box 20, Folder 355)
    - Leonardo Ultramarino, no date (Box 21, Folder 356)
    - Loredano (Delhi); Morozzo; Fontana, 1954-1977, no date (Box 21, Folder 357)
    - Moneta, no date (Box 21, Folder 358-359)
    - Oliviero Illioni, 1975-1977, no date (Box 21, Folder 360)
    - Prato. Los Angeles conferences on economy and culture, 1975-1976 (Box 21, Folder 361)
    - "The Three Ages of the Italian Renaissance", 1970 (Box 21, Folder 362)
    - "Three Ages of the Renaissance", no date (Box 21, Folder 363)
  - Reviews
    - Birth of Europe, 1962-1968 (Box 21, Folder 364-365)
    - Miscellaneous, 1932-1955 (Box 21, Folder 366)
- Additional material, 1960s-1970s; Accession 2009-M-006
  Materials are research files, predominantly in French and Italian.
  - Recherches sur l'architecture domestique et économique au Moyen Age
    Files arranged alphabetically by name of city or town, and contain research notes and photographs with captions.
    - Airvault - Antigny (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bellac - Brux (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Celle-L'Evescault - Châtellerault (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Châtillon - Civray (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Comporte - Jazeneuil (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Joue-Les-Tours - Les Magnils-Reigniers (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Lhommaizé - Lussac-Les-Châteaux (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Marcay - Moncontour (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Montmorillon - Noblat (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Parthenay (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Parthenay - Poitiers (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Poitiers (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Poitiers - Pressac (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Rancon - Saint Junien (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Saint Junien - Saint Léonard de Noblat (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Saint Mandé - Sommières-du-Clain (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Taizon - Voulon (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, printed ephemera, bibliographies, publications, and slides of towns throughout Europe and Asia Minor, 1960s-1970s, undated (Box 5, Folder 1-50)
  - Research files on Italian towns
    - Lists of buildings
      - Abruzzi - Molise, general (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Aquila (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Ascoli Piceno (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Assisi (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Bologna, Emilia-Romagna, general (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Cividale (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Cremona (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Ferrara and Pomposa (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Padova (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Palermo (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Reggio Emilia (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - San Gimignano (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Sulmona (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Treviso (Box 6, Folder 14-28)
      - Vercelli (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - Viterbo (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - Zara (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - Miscellaneous: houses, objects (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Descriptions of buildings
      - Bevagna (Box 6, Folder 33)
      - Bevagna - Campello (Box 6, Folder 34)
      - Castel Ritaldi (Box 6, Folder 35)
      - Castel Santangelo - Cerreto di Spoleto (Box 6, Folder 36)
      - Cerreto di Spoleto - Giano Dell'Umbria (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Giano Dell'Umbria (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Lenano (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Montefalco (Box 7, Folder 4-6)
      - Mantemartano (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Morcicchia - Preci (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - San Giacomo di Spoleto - Silvignano (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Spoleto (Box 8, Folder 3-6)
      - Triponzo - Umbriano, Genoa (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Albums of photographs and maps of buildings
    - Montemolino (Comune di Todi) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Pontecuti (Todi) (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Todi (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Todi (Box 10, Folder 1)